Airat Yusuff

<u>airahyusuff@gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u>

07934570962 <u>Portfolio</u>

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with about three years of experience building user-focused web applications, now seeking opportunities where I can effectively utilise my existing technical skills to contribute to building solutions that make a difference. I am an avid learner with a proven collaborative mindset, good written and verbal communication skills, and I thrive in work environments that provide opportunities for career growth and embrace diversity potentials.

SKILLS

Software: JavaScript, React, Gatsby, Nodejs, Java, Vue, Nuxt, SCSS, SQL, Neo4j, GraphQL, Git.

Cloud: AWS, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux.

Interest Areas: Infrastructure-as-Code, Containerisation, CI/CD.

WORK EXPERIENCE

January 2022 - September 2022 | Frontend Engineer (Remote) - Cova Inc., Washington D.C.

- Top "engineering team" employee for the 2022 Q2 performance evaluation.
- Developed the company's internal reporting tool which captured 7 extensive metrics, resulting in better aggregated reports for the growth/marketing team.
- Integrated 4 major product features and revamped existing features for optimal functionality and better user experience.
- Assisted with GitHub Actions deployment workflows for 2 web apps.

July 2020 - August 2021 | Frontend Developer - SWIPE Limited, Nigeria

- Optimised existing codebase of a payment web app and built 4 new functionalities within 1 month of working with React and Redux.
- Built web apps with optimised user experience for 3 clients in the banking sector within 1 year, leading to increased generated revenue during the pandemic.
- Delivered detailed feedback reports to improve work efficiency and communication within teams.

June 2019 - May 2020 | Web Developer - Mental Care Foundation, Nigeria

- Designed and developed the organization's main website.
- Built an emotional support web app with live chat functionality, establishing volunteers and members participation.

EDUCATION

- M.Sc. Computing (Software Engineering) University of Northampton | Sep 2022 Sep 2023
- Cloud DevOps Engineer Nanodegree Udacity | July 2022
- Programming for Data Science with Python Nanodegree Udacity | November 2021
- B.Sc. (Honours) Computer Engineering Obafemi Awolowo University | Feb 2020
 - Best Graduating Student, Department of Computer Science and Engineering
 - 4.77/5.0 CGPA

CERTIFICATIONS

Sep 2022 | AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Aug 2022 - Present | AWS Community Builder

- Create technical content on AWS concepts and services for the benefit of the community.
- Utilise provided resources to learn and gain more skills in AWS services and ecosystem.

Mar 2023 - Present | University of Northampton Postgraduate Student Representative

- Participated in student reps meetings with course leader to share student feedback on teaching and suggestions for improving overall student experience.
- Advocate for the needs and concerns of fellow students by proactively gathering their feedback and ensuring their concerns were addressed in a timely and effective manner.

CLOUD PROJECTS

January 2023 | Deploy a Web App using Terraform

- Converted AWS CloudFormation templates for deploying a highly available web server to Terraform scripts.
- Set up modules for security, networking, load balancers and auto-scaling services.

December 2022 | Deploy APIs to AWS EKS Cluster

- Extended the functionality for a Go app that exposes an API to return requested values from Fibonacci sequence.
- Reimplemented app in Node.js to have multiple APIs for the deployment.
- · Wrote configuration files and shell scripts to deploy the apps to an AWS EKS cluster using kubectl.
- Built Docker images for the apps and used Docker Compose to start the apps for testing.

September 2022 | Operationalise a Machine Learning Microservice API

 Containerised a Flask app that serves out predictions about housing prices through API calls using Docker and deployed to Minikube and AWS EKS.

July 2022 | UdaPeople

- Built a CI/CD pipeline for a full-stack NodeJS application using the Blue-Green deployment flow.
- Provisioned AWS infrastructures using CloudFormation (EC2, S3, RDS, CloudFront).
- Automated infrastructure configuration using Ansible, and the entire pipeline with CircleCl and GitHub Actions.

June 2022 | Deploy a High-Availability Web App

- Automated the infrastructure deployment process for a highly available web app using AWS CloudFormation.
- Set up network and security configurations, web servers with auto-scaling groups, load balancers for traffic distribution and other AWS services required for high resiliency and availability.

WEB PROJECTS

Teume Project - A KPOP group fan website with YouTube APIs integrations. https://treasureproject.netlify.app/

MCF - A non-profit organisation website. https://formermcf.netlify.app/

Fitila – An anonymous chat platform for a non-profit organisation web https://fitila.mentalcare.life

AutiMS - A therapy reports app and progress tracker (PWA). https://autims.netlify.app/

Callerview Admin - Admin dashboard for Callerview. https://callerview.netlify.app

FilterPay - A webpage that tracks user payments and activities. https://filter-pay.netlify.app

KhayY - A web-based online shopping platform. https://shop.khairahscorner.com/